MICHAEL TORONTOW

mtorontow0@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/michael-torontow · torontow.github.io/MT-Portfolio · 647-929-2341

As a developer, I aspire to combine my twenty years' experience as a theatre artist with my skills and knowledge in web development to innovate within the arts industry in beyond.

EXPERIENCE

DECEMBER 2020 – PRESENT: PROJECT MANAGER/WEB DEVELOPER, TALK IS FREE THEATRE

- Developed a clear, sensible and achievable work proposal to design and build The Canadian Musical Theatre Databasedevoted to promoting Canadian musical theatre composers and their works to theatre producers and educators across Canada and the world--with a target deployment date of July 1, 2021;
- o Manage a staff of researchers and consultants across Canada while adhering to a limited budget, dependent on grants from arts funding organizations;
- o Develop, design, and build the site using HTML, CSS, JS, MongoDB, Express and more, working within budget constraints to contract out freelance coding support as needed.

JULY 2020 - DECEMBER 2020: LITERARY MANAGER, TALK IS FREE THEATRE

o Reporting to the TIFT artistic producer, delivered concise and comprehensive assessments of new scripts, submitted to the company by established and aspiring playwrights alike, for the sake of future presentation or production.

OCTOBER 2019 - PRESENT: PROFESSIONAL THEATRE DIRECTOR, MULTIPLE PRODUCTIONS

- o Draw from research and experience to create and execute the artistic vision of a theatrical production in conjunction with a team of designers, producers and actors for the ultimate purpose of public performance or workshop;
- o Years of experience as an actor facilitate excellent communication with others, making it easier to guide story-telling and to maintain artistic vision and integrity while demonstrating reliable leadership company members can trust.

JANUARY 2002 - PRESENT: PROFESSIONAL ACTOR, MULTIPLE PRODUCTIONS

- o Appeared in dozens of musicals, television series, commercials and industrial productions across Canada, the US, the UK and Australia, consistently displaying exemplary work ethic, commitment and leadership;
- o Nominated across the country for several awards of excellence, and won the SA Bank Best of Fringe: Theatre award for a solo performance at the esteemed Adelaide Fringe Festival, 2020;

EDUCATION

<u>APRIL 2021:</u> **FULL STACK FLEX WEB DEVELOPMENT**, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO SCHOOL OF CONTINUING STUDIES

- o Currently maintaining an A- average, studying HTML, CSS, JS, EXPRESS, NODE, MySQL, and Mongo, among others;
- o Frequently volunteer participation in class and display leadership in group exercises and projects.

OCTOBER 2002: BACHELOR OF ARTS IN THEATRE + CERTIFICATE IN ARTS ADMINISTRATION, UNIVERSITY OF OTTAWA

o Received a comprehensive theatre education in both official languages of Canada, studying technical theatre as well as finding opportunities to tailor the program to focus on my goal of performing in musical theatre professionally.

SKILLS

o Excellent leader, reliable team player, effective communicator and motivator; adaptable, organized, positive.

ACTIVITIES

In addition to my current pursuits, I am apprenticing with the artistic producer of Talk Is Free Theatre to create and run my own theatre production company, with a focus on immersive theatre and fostering connections with marginalized creators otherwise "forgotten" by leading artistic organizations in the Hamilton, Ontario, region.

I have been commissioned to write a new theatre production, which will have a primary focus on mental health.

I have a strong working knowledge of French, have studied Spanish and German, enjoy travel, hiking and other outdoor activities in my neighbourhood, including raising chickens and ducks in my backyard, and sharing fresh eggs with the neighbours.